Finding Aid for the Aron Kuppermann Papers 1946-2012
Caltech Archives
Aron Kuppermann Papers,
1946-2012
10269-MS
Kuppermann, Aron 1926-2011
47 linear feet
California Institute of Technology. Caltech Archives Pasadena, California 91125
Aron Kuppermann (1926-2011) was a leader in the field of computational chemistry and was best known for his theoretical studies of the dynamics of chemical reactions. During his many years at Caltech (1963-2011), Kuppermann also worked as a consultant for the World Bank on projects of Science and Technology in Brazil, China, Mexico, Argentina, Chile, and Uganda from 1983 to 2005. His papers reflect his avid interest in both scientific research and teaching.
Access
The collection is open to researchers with the exception of three files (29.8, 31.6, and 31.7) that remain closed indefinitely for reasons of confidentiality and privacy. Researchers must apply in writing for access.
Acquisition Information
The Aron Kuppermann Papers were given to the Caltech Archives by Mrs. Roza Kuppermann, Aron Kuppermann's widow, in 2012-2013.
Biography
Aron Kuppermann was born in São Paulo, Brazil on May 6, 1926. He received his BS in Chemical Engineering in 1948, and another in Civil Engineering in 1952, both from the University of São Paulo. In 1955 he received his Ph.D. in Physical Chemistry from the University of Notre Dame. From 1955 to 1963 he taught at the University of Illinois. He was appointed professor of Physical Chemistry at the California Institute of Technology in 1963, where he spent the rest of his academic career until his retirement in 2010.
Along his academic career, Professor Kupperman worked as a consultant for many organizations such as the Argonne National Laboratory, the Armour Research Foundation, and Instituto de Energia Atómica in São Paulo, Brazil, the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, and the World Bank.
Kuppermann was a member of the advisory board of the International Journal for Radiation Physics and Chemistry (1968-1976) and a member of the editorial board of the Journal of Physical Chemistry (1965-1970). He was a member of the Joint U.S.-Brazil Science Cooperation Program on Graduate Teaching and Research in Chemistry between 1969 and 1973 and served as its chairman from 1973 until 1976.
Scope and Content
The Kuppermann Papers have been divided into nine series, organized in one hundred and eight archival boxes: Correspondence (1); World Bank (2); California Institute of Technology (3); Teaching (4); Writings and Publications (5); Talks, Conferences, and Meetings (6); Research Files (7); Computing (8); and Biographical and Personal Material (9).
Series 1, Correspondence, is divided into two subseries. The first one contains mail logs of Kuppermann's incoming and outgoing mail from 1989 until 2011. The second subseries contains the actual correspondence ranges from the early 1950s to 2010, organized in chronological order, as was kept by Professor Kuppermann himself. Researchers may use the mail logs as a reference index to help them navigate this series. In the fall of 1953, while a graduate student at the University of Notre Dame, Kuppermann sent out letters to a number of prominent physicists, such as, Albert Einstein, Enrico Fermi, W. Heisenberg, Wolfgang Pauli, Leonard Isaac Schiff, and Inge-Ernst Sommerfeld. Copies of this unique correspondence can be found in series 8, Box 105.11, entitled: Seminar on Bohm's paper.
Kuppermann's massive involvement with the World Bank is documented in Series 2. From 1983 to 2005 he worked for this organization as a consultant on projects of Science and Technology. He was responsible for reviewing progress in the implementation of the chemistry and chemical engineering, biotechnology, and geosciences programs in Brazil, China, Mexico, Argentina, Chile, and Uganda. Folders in this series are arranged by the World Bank specific mission in a chronological order and contain correspondence, reports, travel documents, and support material related to the specific mission.
Kuppermann's massive involvement with the World Bank is documented in Series 2. From 1983 to 2005 he worked for this organization as a consultant on projects of Science and Technology. He was responsible for reviewing progress in the implementation of the chemistry and chemical engineering, biotechnology, and geosciences programs in Brazil, China, Mexico, Argentina, Chile, and Uganda. Folders in this series are arranged by the World Bank specific mission in a chronological order and contain correspondence, reports, travel documents, and support material related to the specific mission.
Professor Kuppermann's passion for teaching is documented in series 4. This series contains his teaching material from the University of Illinois (1955-1963) and Caltech (1970-2010). Kuppermann taught many classes yet his signature course at Caltech was Chemistry 125. Researchers can find here his lecture notes, as well as class assignments and exams. He was awarded the 1999 Excellence in Mentoring Award by the Caltech Graduate Student Council (GSC) and the Classroom Teaching Award in 2010.
Series 5, Writings and Publications, is divided into two subseries. The first one contains Kuppermann's unpublished manuscripts (in Portuguese and English) and reviews of manuscripts and proposals of others. The second subseries contains Kuppermann's reprints arrange in chronological order according to his list of publications that can be found in Series 9, Biographical and Personal Material (Folder 104.10) .Folders in this series contain a wide variety of related documents, from graphs and illustrations to calculations and related correspondence.
Kuppermann's travel files were organized within Series 6. They include his talks and lectures in conferences and meetings. A wide variety of talk-related documents, from talk outlines and notes to related correspondence, are organized in chronological order. For a complete view of Kuppermann's travel files researchers may want to consult his appointment books located in Series 9, Biographical and Personal Material (Folders 108.13-108.16).
Series 7, Research Files, is divided into two subseries. The first one contains proposals and grants Kuppermann submitted to a variety of organizations in order to fund his research over the years. The second subseries contain Kuppermann's technical files.
Kuppermann's interest in the dynamics of chemical reactions led him to use supercomputers in his research for predicting the cross sections and rates of chemical reactions from first quantum mechanical principles. Series 8 shows Kuppermann's involvement with parallel computers research at San Diego Supercomputer Center (SDSC) and Caltech.
Series 9, Biographical and Personal Material, includes records of Kuppermann's early and later education, biographical listings, awards and honors, news clippings, and interviews.
For further biographical information, researchers should refer to his oral history, conducted by Shirley K. Cohen between July-November 2001, which is deposited in the Caltech Archives. An online version can be found online at: http://resolver.caltech.edu/CaltechOH:OH_Kuppermann_A.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Correspondence
Series 2. World Bank 1983- 2005
Series 3. California Institute of Technology
Series 4. Teaching
Series 5. Writings and Publications
Series 6. Talks and Meetings
Series 7. Research Files
Series 8. Computing
Series 9. Biographical and Personal Material
Container List
- Correspondence, Series 1.
  - Incoming and outgoing mail logs, Subseries 1.
    - Mail log:1989, November 17 - December 29, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mail log:1990, January 2 - December 28, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mail log:1991, January 2 - December 26, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mail log:1992, January 2 - December 28, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mail log:1993, January 4 - December 29, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mail log:1994, January 3 - December 30, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mail log:1995, January 3 - December 28, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Mail log:1996, January 2 - December 19, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mail log:1997, January 3 - December 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mail log:1998, January 5 - December 31, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mail log:1999, January 1 - December 28, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mail logs: 2004-2006, January 13, 2004-21 December 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mail logs: 2007-2011, January 7, 2007-24 August, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, Subseries 2.
    - Correspondence 1953-1984
    - correspondence, 1953-1954, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence 1985
    - January, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - February, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - March, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - April, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - May, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - June, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - July, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - August, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - September, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - October, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - November, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - December, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence 1986
    - January, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - February, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - March, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - April, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - May, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - June, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - July, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - August, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - September, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence 1987
    - January, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - February, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - March, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - April, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - May, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - June, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - July, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - August, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - September, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - October, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - November, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - December, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence 1988
    - January, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - February, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - March, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - April, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - May, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - June, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - July, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - August, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - September, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - October, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - November, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - December, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence 1989
    - January, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - February, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - March, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - April, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - May, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - June, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - July, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - August, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - September, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - October, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - November, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - December, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence 1990
    - January, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - February, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - March, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - April, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - May, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - June, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - July, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - August, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - September, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - October, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - November, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - December, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence 1991
    - January, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - February, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - March, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - April, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - May, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - June, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - July, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - August, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - September, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - October, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - November, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - December, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence 1992
    - January, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - February, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - March, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - April, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - May, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - June, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - July, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - August, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - September, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - October, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - November, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - December, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence 1993
    - January, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - February, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - March, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - April, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - May, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - June, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - July, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - August, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - September, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - October 1-15, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - October 16-30, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - November 1-15, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - November 16-30, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - December 1-15, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - December 16-31, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence 1994
    - January, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - February, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - March, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - April, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - May 1-10, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - May 11-31, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - June 1-15, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - June 16-30, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - July, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - August, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - September, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - October, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - November 1-15, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - November 16-30, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - December 1-15, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - December 16-31, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence 1995
    - January 1-15, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - January 1-15, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - February 1-15, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - February 16-28, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - March 1-15, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - March 16-31, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - April 1-15, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - April 16-30, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - May 1-15, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - May 16-31, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - June 1-15, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - June 16-30, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - July, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - August, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - September, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - October, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - November, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - December, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence 1996
    - January, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - February, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - March, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - April, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - May, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - June, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - July, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - August, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - September, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - October, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - November, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - December, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence 1997
    - January, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - February, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - March, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - April, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - May, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - June, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - July, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - August, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - September, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - October, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - November, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - December, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence 1998
    - January, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - February, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - March, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - April, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - May, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - June-December, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence 1999
    - January-June, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - July-August, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence 2000
    - January-December, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - January-December, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - January-December, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - January-December, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - January-December, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - January-December, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - January-December, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - January-December, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - January-December, 2008-2010 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- World Bank 1983- 2005, Series 2.
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1983-1984
  - Correspondence and travel related documents, January 1983- August 1984 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Working paper: World Bank sector loan to Brazil for science and technology: research and graduate training programs, March 30, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Staff appraisal report: Brazil sector project for science and technology, June 18, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Report no. 5153.
  - Appraisal report: World Bank project loan to Brazil for science and technology: research and graduate training programs, July 31, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Project code 6BRAEE07.
  - Staff appraisal report: Brazil sector project for science and technology, August 3, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Staff appraisal report: Brazil sector project for science and technology, November 29, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1985
  - Travel related documents, January 1985 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Postpartum notes: Brazil sector project for science and technology, January 30, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Situation report: Brazil sector project for science and technology, April 1, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Brazil science and technology supervision mission: Loan 2489-BR, July 1, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - First supervision mission: Aide memoire, July 17-August 15, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Supervision report: Brazil science and technology supervision mission Loan 2489-BR, October 16, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1986
  - Supervision mission: Aide memoire, August 11-22, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Full supervision report: Brazil science and technology supervision mission Loan 2489-BR, September 16, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Travel related documents, November 10, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1987
  - Notes for the World Bank midterm review mission, January 18, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Midterm review mission, January 29, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Supervision mission: Aide memoire, February 11, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Travel related documents, June 26, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1988
  - Correspondence and support material, October 1987- February 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Supervision mission: Aide memoire, March 28, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Full supervision report: Brazil science and technology supervision mission Loan 2489-BR, March 31, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Travel related documents, June 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - World Bank Mission to China 1988
  - Correspondence and support material, September-October 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Travel related documents, October 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - World Bank Mission to China: May-June 1989
  - Travel related documents, April 1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - China Key Studies Development Project: Correspondence and support material, May 1989 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Meetings notes, May 16-June 3, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - China Proposed Key Studies Development Project: Aide memoire, June 2, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Staff appraisal report: China Key Studies Development Project, July 24, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil: June-July 1989
  - Correspondence and support material, October 1988- July 1989 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Travel related documents, June 1989 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Meetings notes, June 26-July 11, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Brazil supervision mission, July 7, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Brazil science and technology supervision mission (Loan 2489-BR): Aide memoire, July 12, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - World Bank Mission to China: September 1989
  - Travel related documents, August 1989 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence and support material, August-September 1989 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Meetings notes, September 4-23, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - China Proposed Key Studies Development Project: Aide memoire, September 19, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil: October-November 1989
  - Travel related documents, September 1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and support material, September- December 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Staff appraisal report: Brazil, Third Agricultural Research Project, September 11, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Report no. 7991-BR.
  - Meetings notes, October-November 1989 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry and chemical engineering sub-program notes, November 5, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Biochemistry sub-program notes, November 6, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Operations basic document and operations manual, November 7, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT): Aide memoire, November 9, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT): Reference material I, November- December 1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT): Reference material II, November- December 1989 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT): Reference material III, November- December 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT): Reference material IV, November- December 1989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1990
  - Correspondence and support material, May - July 1990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Travel related documents, May - June 1990 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Meetings notes, June 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Support Program for Scientific and Technological Development (PADCT) Phase II: Aide memoire, June 15, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Staff appraisal report: Brazil, Science Research and training Project, June 22, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Report no. 8811-BR.
  - Brazil Mission: Reference material, June - July 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - World Bank Mission to Mexico: January-February 1991
  - Travel related documents, January - February 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and support material, January - March 1991 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Meetings notes, January - February 1991 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Mexico Industrial Modernization and Technology Development Project: Aide memoire, February 6, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - World Bank Mission to Mexico: June 1991
  - Correspondence and support material, May-November, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Travel related documents, June 1991 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Meetings notes, June 1991 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil 1991
  - Correspondence and support material, June- September 1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Travel related documents, August 1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Report: Investment in Science Research and Training, September 1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    "Views from LATHR, No. 19"
  - World Bank Mission to Mexico 1992
  - Correspondence and support material, December 1991-January 1992 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Comments on revised PACIME documents (Programa de Apoyo a la Ciencia en Mexico), January 22-24, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Staff appraisal report: Mexico, Science and Technology Infrastructure Project, April 30, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Report no. 10468-ME.
  - "Reglas de Operacion del PACIME", 1992 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Report in Spanish.
  - "PACIME: Programa de Apoyo a la Ciencia en Mexico", 1992 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Report published by the National Council of Science and Technology of Mexico in Spanish.